# NWANOSIKE TOCHUKWU EMMANUEL

No 10 Ezeolisa Street, Onitsha South, Anambra State | Nwanosiketochukwu99@gmail.com 08148280097, 09076249114

# **SUMMARY**

A versatile professional with a robust background in technical and soft skills and experience in education, research, and technology. Notably, I contributed to teaching innovations that enhanced student engagement, research into antibiotic-resistant bacteria, and a 10% sales increase in the pharmaceutical sector. My recent work as a Frontend Developer Intern and professional certifications in AI and software development showcase my commitment to continuous learning and development.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Nigeria Nsukka | Bachelor of Science

Enugu, Nigeria | 2017 - 2022

Cumulative GPA: 4.4/5.0

Immaculate Heart of Mary, Secondary School

• Senior School Certificate

Anambra, Nigeria | 2010 - 2016

### **SKILLS**

• Technical Skills	<ul> <li>✓ Programming language</li> <li>✓ Software tools</li> <li>✓ Al tools</li> <li>Javascript and Reactjs</li> <li>Excel, Google workspace</li> <li>Chatgpt, Canva, RunwayML</li> </ul>	
• Soft Skills	<ul><li>✓ Excellent communication skills</li><li>✓ Analytical and Problem solving</li></ul>	
	✓ Team player	
	✓ Time management	
	✓ Attention to details	

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Apostolic Faith Secondary School** | *Teaching Assistant*

Kogi, Nigeria | **2023 – 2024** 

(National Youth Service Corp)

- Collaborated with colleagues to implement new teaching strategies, resulting in a 10% increase in student retention and understanding of key concepts.
- Mentored a WAEC candidate in physics, developing a structured study plan and regular assessments that led to the candidate's successful performance in the exam
- Assessed student performance and tailored instruction to meet diverse learning needs, resulting to better performance of the student

# (Student Project Work)

 Contributed to better understanding of the environmental dissemination of antibiotic-resistance bacteria by identifying high levels antibiotic resistance and diverse plasmid profiles among sewageborne isolates of Escherichia coli and Klebsiella pneumonia

**Department of Microbiology, Faculty Veterinary** | Laboratory Technician Enugu, Nigeria | **2019** 

(Industrial Training)

 Successfully isolated and identified a novel bacterial strain from water sample, demonstrating proficiency in laboratory techniques and contributing to laboratory's research goals

# Sampson Pharmaceutical Company | Sales Assistant

Anambra, Nigeria | **2015 – 2017** 

• Increased sales by 10% within 5months by implementing effective customer strategies, resulting in improved customer retention and positive word-of-mouth referrals

## **CodeAlpha Company** | Frontend developer intern

Enugu, Nigeria | 2022

(Virtual Internship)

• Collaborated with team members to brainstorm ideas, plan project scope, and implement design specifications.

#### OTHER PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES

- African Leadership Academy, AI Career Essential, 2024
- Introduction to Career Skills in Software Development

#### **REFERENCES**

Will be made available upon request.